<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>K&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://vakarthik.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on K&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://vakarthik.com/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://vakarthik.com/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vakarthik.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HTTPS for Homelab using Caddy and ACME DNS</title>
      <link>https://vakarthik.com/posts/2021/compiling-and-building-caddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vakarthik.com/posts/2021/compiling-and-building-caddy/</guid>
      <description>HTTPS for Homelab When I wanted to install bitwarden_rs (now vaultwarden), i read their wiki and got struck with an idea to setup my homelab apps behind https.
Then the hunt for reverse proxies started and i settled down with caddy after trying out nginx and traefik (both are good, but not suitable for my usecase). Caddy is a simple configurable reverse proxy and webserver. I use it as reverse proxy and HTTPS provider for all my homelab apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homelab v1</title>
      <link>https://vakarthik.com/posts/2019/homelab-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vakarthik.com/posts/2019/homelab-2019/</guid>
      <description>Intro ping 127.0.0.1
There are some interests which do not change! I used to write html and css in college days. I have had shared hosting accounts, VPS and so on! I still remember creating a small site for college workshop using WordPress. I learnt web development and managing VPS through youtube. I have always wanted to host on my own server and somehow have managed to do it this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://vakarthik.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vakarthik.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Full time engineer, part-time learner.
This site is a result of my interest towards computers, networks etc., and a memory of my lost love for photos. Also this has evolved from time to time based on my skills. When i was creating my personal site back in college days, i used to write in html and css. Now after 10 years so much has changed and i write in markdown!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos</title>
      <link>https://vakarthik.com/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vakarthik.com/photos/</guid>
      <description>        </description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
